<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: programming | some guy on the Internet]]></title>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-02T20:42:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Huff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Had One Job]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/you-had-one-job/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-02T20:06:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/you-had-one-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the way home today I encountered one of our housemates, also homeward bound, and as we came in the front door I was chattering happily about my second day at work.  I have tasks!  Tasks that I can perform!  This is really exciting.</p>

<p>I was, however, interrupted mid-sentence by a crash from the hallway, where Elijah (one of our cats) had knocked a box of tissues from the shelf to the floor.  He was standing by it staring at me, and I got the distinct sense that this was a warning shot across my bows, indicating that I should shut up about trivialities and focus on the much more important topic of his dinner.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="images/one_job.jpg" width="746" height="550" title="&ldquo;you had one job&rdquo;" ></p>

<h3>Vim, Pathogen, and dirty submodules</h3>

<p>Earlier today I had been adding Vim plugins to my dotfiles repository, pulling them in as <a href="http://git-scm.com/docs/git-submodule">Git submodules</a> for use with <a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen">Pathogen</a>.  I installed a couple of plugins and then generated the Vim help tags for them, which led to a minor unsightliness when the generated tags file showed up as untracked changes in my dotfiles directory.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/tpope">Tim Pope</a> suggests working around this problem by setting a <a href="http://git-scm.com/docs/gitignore">global excludes file</a>, but I am vaguely concerned that this will just create a landmine that I will step on at some future time when I want to be capturing some entirely unrelated file called <code>tags</code>.  Instead I discovered that <a href="http://www.nils-haldenwang.de/frameworks-and-tools/git/how-to-ignore-changes-in-git-submodules">this fellow has the exact same problem</a>, and his solution works great for me.  Thanks, Nils!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Expressions of Emotion in GitHub Commit Messages]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/expressions-of-emotion-in-github-commit-messages/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-30T18:30:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/expressions-of-emotion-in-github-commit-messages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m mad with power!  I have <a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudFront/latest/APIReference/">CloudFront API access</a> and I&rsquo;m not afraid to use it!  I sound my <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Song_of_Myself">barbaric yawp</a> over the roofs of the world!</p>

<p>Reading the documentation for the <a href="http://osrc.dfm.io/">Open Source Report Card</a> led me to the following gem:</p>

<h3><a href="http://geeksta.net/geeklog/exploring-expressions-emotions-github-commit-messages/">Exploring Expressions of Emotion in GitHub Commit Messages</a></h3>

<p>It is exactly what it sounds like; NLP plus stats plus the GitHub datastream.  Some of my favorite bits:</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;What stands out in the anger chart compared to the rest is the prominent gap between the "most angry language&rdquo; VimL and the other languages."</li>
<li>&ldquo;regexes are fun and pleasant to work with, in the same way that oranges are purple&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;lol, I dunno what I&rsquo;m doing (JavaScript)&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;Still, I&rsquo;m a bit surprised of the result, not because Perl is the winner, but because PHP does not seem to surprise people that often, which does not reflect my experience with this language at all.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>Seriously, just go read it.  It&rsquo;s awesome.</p>

<p>-steve</p>

<p>P.S. And of course, the section on swearing made me think of <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060529181955/http://blog.airdrop.org/archives/000014.html">The Terrible Mr. Grimshaw</a> (audio, NSFW).  Hooray once again for <a href="https://archive.org">archive.org</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
