<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[some guy on the Internet]]></title>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-02T19:28:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Huff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First day at RunKeeper]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/first-day-at-runkeeper/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-01T22:57:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/first-day-at-runkeeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m winding down at the end of my first day at <a href="http://runkeeper.com">RunKeeper</a>, and I&rsquo;m still walking on air :)  Today started with me apparently being a bit jittery while shaving this morning:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://someguyontheinter.net/images/shaving_cuts.jpg" width="240" height="320" title="&#34;ouch&#34;" alt="&#34;ouch&#34;"></p>

<p>and ended with me running (while wearing <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Sanita-457806M-20-Professional-Cabrio-Clog/dp/B001CWYZME">clogs</a>, ow) to North Station to catch the commuter rail, and today was STILL awesome.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s really good to work with my old boss Matt again, and I&rsquo;m really liking the generally happy atmosphere, and the tiny dog wandering around the office, and I&rsquo;ve already come up with some tasks I want to try to get my arms around in the near future.  Plus I didn&rsquo;t break anything on the first day!</p>

<p>I spent a chunk of the past week building my new laptop by means of <a href="https://boxen.github.com">Boxen</a>, and I really like this approach to workstation management.  A lot of the work I&rsquo;ve been doing during the past few years focuses on server and application automation, and as a result my servers tend to be (relatively) neat and well-ordered while my laptop is a wretched hive of scum and villainy; if I recall correctly, the laptop that I handed in last week contained the fifth generation of a lovingly hand-crafted workstation configuration, which started out as a Mac OS X 10.2 installation on a PowerPC Mac laptop and underwent multiple ordeals of Migration Assistant/Carbon Copy Cloner/etc. to attain its final Mac OS X 10.7 on Intel status, accumulating tons of cruft as it went.</p>

<p>So now my workstation config lives in a GitHub repository, and deploying it onto a new machine is remarkably straightforward.  I have about 70% of what I need captured in code; now I just need to be reasonably diligent about keeping up with changes I make post-installation, and next time around I will be much happier.</p>

<p>Current ruling on Boxen:</p>

<p>Pro:</p>

<ul>
<li>configuration captured in code</li>
<li>safe to re-apply config repeatedly</li>
<li>upstream maintainers quite responsive to pull requests</li>
</ul>


<p>Con:</p>

<ul>
<li>no simple way to handle apps that require post-installation configuration (maybe capture <code>.plist</code> files in the repo as templates? yuck)</li>
<li><em>really</em> does not play nicely with multiple local users on the same host (I may have to end up abandoning my habit of maintaining one user account for work and one for personal use, and leveraging <a href="http://www.controlplaneapp.com">ControlPlane</a> to compensate)</li>
</ul>


<p>-steve</p>

<p>P.S. Oh right, I had also stumbled belatedly onto this Garamond silliness via <a href="http://www.thomasphinney.com/2014/03/saving-400m-font/">this excellent refutation</a>.  My only contribution to the debate, such as it is, is to suggest that Garamond is weaksauce and that real toner-savers use <a href="http://ecofont.com/">Ecofont</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Expressions of Emotion in GitHub Commit Messages]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/expressions-of-emotion-in-github-commit-messages/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-30T18:30:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/expressions-of-emotion-in-github-commit-messages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m mad with power!  I have <a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudFront/latest/APIReference/">CloudFront API access</a> and I&rsquo;m not afraid to use it!  I sound my <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Song_of_Myself">barbaric yawp</a> over the roofs of the world!</p>

<p>Reading the documentation for the <a href="http://osrc.dfm.io/">Open Source Report Card</a> led me to the following gem:</p>

<h3><a href="http://geeksta.net/geeklog/exploring-expressions-emotions-github-commit-messages/">Exploring Expressions of Emotion in GitHub Commit Messages</a></h3>

<p>It is exactly what it sounds like; NLP plus stats plus the GitHub datastream.  Some of my favorite bits:</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;What stands out in the anger chart compared to the rest is the prominent gap between the &#8220;most angry language&rdquo; VimL and the other languages.&#8221;</li>
<li>&ldquo;regexes are fun and pleasant to work with, in the same way that oranges are purple&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;lol, I dunno what I&rsquo;m doing (JavaScript)&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;Still, I&rsquo;m a bit surprised of the result, not because Perl is the winner, but because PHP does not seem to surprise people that often, which does not reflect my experience with this language at all.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>Seriously, just go read it.  It&rsquo;s awesome.</p>

<p>-steve</p>

<p>P.S. And of course, the section on swearing made me think of <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060529181955/http://blog.airdrop.org/archives/000014.html">The Terrible Mr. Grimshaw</a> (audio, NSFW).  Hooray once again for <a href="https://archive.org">archive.org</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-30T12:43:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apparently it is high time I had an actual blog.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>How The Sausage Is Made</h2>

<p>This blog is written, generated, and published via the following stack:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.vim.org">Vim</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/plasticboy/vim-markdown">vim-markdown</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-git">vim-git</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/scrooloose/vim-fugitive">fugitive</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/erikzaadi/solarized-octopress-theme">Solarized Octopress Theme</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3">AWS S3</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront">AWS CloudFront</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/laurilehmijoki/s3_website">s3_website</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
