<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cats | some guy on the Internet]]></title>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/categories/cats/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-02T21:37:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Huff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Had One Job]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/you-had-one-job/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-02T20:06:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/you-had-one-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the way home today I encountered one of our housemates, also homeward bound, and as we came in the front door I was chattering happily about my second day at work.  I have tasks!  Tasks that I can perform!  This is really exciting.</p>

<p>I was, however, interrupted mid-sentence by a crash from the hallway, where Elijah (one of our cats) had knocked a box of tissues from the shelf to the floor.  He was standing by it staring at me, and I got the distinct sense that this was a warning shot across my bows, indicating that I should shut up about trivialities and focus on the much more important topic of his dinner.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/one_job.jpg" width="746" height="550" title="&ldquo;you had one job&rdquo;" ></p>

<h3>Vim, Pathogen, and dirty submodules</h3>

<p>Earlier today I had been adding Vim plugins to my dotfiles repository, pulling them in as <a href="http://git-scm.com/docs/git-submodule">Git submodules</a> for use with <a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen">Pathogen</a>.  I installed a couple of plugins and then generated the Vim help tags for them, which led to a minor unsightliness when the generated tags file showed up as untracked changes in my dotfiles directory.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/tpope">Tim Pope</a> suggests working around this problem by setting a <a href="http://git-scm.com/docs/gitignore">global excludes file</a>, but I am vaguely concerned that this will just create a landmine that I will step on at some future time when I want to be capturing some entirely unrelated file called <code>tags</code>.  Instead I discovered that <a href="http://www.nils-haldenwang.de/frameworks-and-tools/git/how-to-ignore-changes-in-git-submodules">this fellow has the exact same problem</a>, and his solution works great for me.  Thanks, Nils!</p>

<p>-steve</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
