<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sysadmin | some guy on the Internet]]></title>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/categories/sysadmin/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T23:32:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Huff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Details About Heartbleed]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/more-details-about-heartbleed/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-09T22:39:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/more-details-about-heartbleed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven&rsquo;t yet <a href="http://heartbleed.com">patched your OpenSSL and regenerated your certs</a>, stop reading and go fix it; it&rsquo;s OK, I&rsquo;ll still be here when you get back.</p>

<p>All set?  OK.  I found an interesting analysis of the bug over at <a href="http://blog.existentialize.com/diagnosis-of-the-openssl-heartbleed-bug.html">this guy Sean Cassidy&rsquo;s blog</a>.  In brief: I have been happy for many years that other people like to write C, because it means both that I get to benefit from their work (basically my entire livelihood is based on the C ecosystem) and also that I generally don&rsquo;t have to write it myself. :)</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/xkcd_1353_heartbleed.png" width="740" height="307" title="&ldquo;XKCD 1353 &ndash; Heartbleed&rdquo;" ></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In other news, I think I accumulated my first piece of <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html">technical debt</a> at the new job today.  I spent a while fighting with <a href="http://blog.jonliv.es/2011/04/26/creating-your-own-signed-apt-repository-and-debian-packages/">signed apt packages</a>; by the time I headed home I had managed to unbreak the repository, but I still have one Java package with an invalid signature, so tomorrow I&rsquo;ll go another few rounds.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PSA: Heartbleed OpenSSL Vulnerability]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/psa-heartbleed-openssl-vulnerability/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-08T16:36:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/psa-heartbleed-openssl-vulnerability</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over dinner last night one of my friends was talking about an OpenSSL vulnerability that had just been disclosed; this morning I took a closer look and decided that I want to boost the signal a bit</p>

<p>The <a href="http://heartbleed.com/">Heartbleed</a> OpenSSL vulnerability affects recent releases of <a href="http://www.openssl.org/">OpenSSL</a>.  Affected systems can be made to reveal secret keys; this is arguably one of the worst ways in which an encryption library can fail, and if you are publishing anything that is secured with SSL (<em>e.g.</em> HTTPS, SMTP/IMAP with TLS, LDAPS, to name a few common uses) and using a vulnerable version, then you should treat your keys as compromised, generate a new private key, and generate new certificates.</p>

<p>If you are not your own sysadmin, then you should find out whether your service providers (including your employer) are reacting appropriately to this issue.  Responsible service providers may proactively publish statements about the issue; if you don&rsquo;t find anything on your provider&rsquo;s website, contact technical support.</p>

<p>More information about this vulnerability can be found by consulting <a href="http://web.nvd.nist.gov/view/vuln/detail?vulnId=CVE-2014-0160">the CERT advisory</a>; there are also some nice StackExchange questions:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/55076/what-should-a-website-operator-do-about-the-heartbleed-openssl-exploit?">http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/55076/what-should-a-website-operator-do-about-the-heartbleed-openssl-exploit?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://serverfault.com/questions/587329/heartbleed-what-is-it-and-what-are-options-to-mitigate-it">https://serverfault.com/questions/587329/heartbleed-what-is-it-and-what-are-options-to-mitigate-it</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Responding to security vulnerabilities is always a tradeoff between effort and threat, but this one seems worth paying attention to.</p>

<p>-steve</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
