<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: signal | some guy on the Internet]]></title>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/categories/signal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T23:07:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Huff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Details About Heartbleed]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/more-details-about-heartbleed/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-09T22:39:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/more-details-about-heartbleed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven&rsquo;t yet <a href="http://heartbleed.com">patched your OpenSSL and regenerated your certs</a>, stop reading and go fix it; it&rsquo;s OK, I&rsquo;ll still be here when you get back.</p>

<p>All set?  OK.  I found an interesting analysis of the bug over at <a href="http://blog.existentialize.com/diagnosis-of-the-openssl-heartbleed-bug.html">this guy Sean Cassidy&rsquo;s blog</a>.  In brief: I have been happy for many years that other people like to write C, because it means both that I get to benefit from their work (basically my entire livelihood is based on the C ecosystem) and also that I generally don&rsquo;t have to write it myself. :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In other news, I think I accumulated my first piece of <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html">technical debt</a> at the new job today.  I spent a while fighting with <a href="http://blog.jonliv.es/2011/04/26/creating-your-own-signed-apt-repository-and-debian-packages/">signed apt packages</a>; by the time I headed home I had managed to unbreak the repository, but I still have one Java package with an invalid signature, so tomorrow I&rsquo;ll go another few rounds.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PSA: Heartbleed OpenSSL Vulnerability]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/psa-heartbleed-openssl-vulnerability/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-08T16:36:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/psa-heartbleed-openssl-vulnerability</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over dinner last night one of my friends was talking about an OpenSSL vulnerability that had just been disclosed; this morning I took a closer look and decided that I want to boost the signal a bit</p>

<p>The <a href="http://heartbleed.com/">Heartbleed</a> OpenSSL vulnerability affects recent releases of <a href="http://www.openssl.org/">OpenSSL</a>.  Affected systems can be made to reveal secret keys; this is arguably one of the worst ways in which an encryption library can fail, and if you are publishing anything that is secured with SSL (<em>e.g.</em> HTTPS, SMTP/IMAP with TLS, LDAPS, to name a few common uses) and using a vulnerable version, then you should treat your keys as compromised, generate a new private key, and generate new certificates.</p>

<p>If you are not your own sysadmin, then you should find out whether your service providers (including your employer) are reacting appropriately to this issue.  Responsible service providers may proactively publish statements about the issue; if you don&rsquo;t find anything on your provider&rsquo;s website, contact technical support.</p>

<p>More information about this vulnerability can be found by consulting <a href="http://web.nvd.nist.gov/view/vuln/detail?vulnId=CVE-2014-0160">the CERT advisory</a>; there are also some nice StackExchange questions:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/55076/what-should-a-website-operator-do-about-the-heartbleed-openssl-exploit?">http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/55076/what-should-a-website-operator-do-about-the-heartbleed-openssl-exploit?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://serverfault.com/questions/587329/heartbleed-what-is-it-and-what-are-options-to-mitigate-it">https://serverfault.com/questions/587329/heartbleed-what-is-it-and-what-are-options-to-mitigate-it</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Responding to security vulnerabilities is always a tradeoff between effort and threat, but this one seems worth paying attention to.</p>

<p>-steve</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PEM Files, for the Last Damn Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/pem-files/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-07T20:49:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/pem-files</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OK, I am tired of forgetting this information and having to re-research it.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/.pem#Certificate_filename_extensions">PEM file</a> is an X.509 digital certificate, specifically a &ldquo;Base64 encoded DER certificate&rdquo; (thank you Wikipedia).  The components are concatenated in the following format:</p>

<ol>
<li>Private key (optional)</li>
<li>Server certificate</li>
<li>Intermediate certificate (optional)</li>
<li>Root certificate (optional)</li>
</ol>


<p>or, in other words, <code>cat server.key server.crt ca-bundle.crt &gt;&gt; server.pem</code>.</p>

<p>That is my final word on the subject.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This evening did not involve attending our intended <a href="http://petermulvey.com/">Peter Mulvey</a> concert, but did involve hanging out at home with various friends and drinking a <a href="http://wiki.webtender.com/wiki/Bourbon_Triple_Sec_Lemon_Juice">Bourble</a>; I hadn&rsquo;t previously encountered this cocktail, but rather mixed it in an attempt to finish off a bottle of triple sec.  It wasn&rsquo;t bad; I found the lemon juice a bit too strong and will use less next time, or maybe lime juice, or maybe a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meyer_lemon">Meyer lemon</a> if I have one handy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First day at RunKeeper]]></title>
    <link href="http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/first-day-at-runkeeper/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-01T22:57:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://someguyontheinter.net/blog/first-day-at-runkeeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m winding down at the end of my first day at <a href="http://runkeeper.com">RunKeeper</a>, and I&rsquo;m still walking on air :)  Today started with me apparently being a bit jittery while shaving this morning:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/shaving_cuts.jpg" width="240" height="320" title="&ldquo;ouch&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>and ended with me running (while wearing <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Sanita-457806M-20-Professional-Cabrio-Clog/dp/B001CWYZME">clogs</a>, ow) to North Station to catch the commuter rail, and today was STILL awesome.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s really good to work with my old boss Matt again, and I&rsquo;m really liking the generally happy atmosphere, and the tiny dog wandering around the office, and I&rsquo;ve already come up with some tasks I want to try to get my arms around in the near future.  Plus I didn&rsquo;t break anything on the first day!</p>

<p>I spent a chunk of the past week building my new laptop by means of <a href="https://boxen.github.com">Boxen</a>, and I really like this approach to workstation management.  A lot of the work I&rsquo;ve been doing during the past few years focuses on server and application automation, and as a result my servers tend to be (relatively) neat and well-ordered while my laptop is a wretched hive of scum and villainy; if I recall correctly, the laptop that I handed in last week contained the fifth generation of a lovingly hand-crafted workstation configuration, which started out as a Mac OS X 10.2 installation on a PowerPC Mac laptop and underwent multiple ordeals of Migration Assistant/Carbon Copy Cloner/etc. to attain its final Mac OS X 10.7 on Intel status, accumulating tons of cruft as it went.</p>

<p>So now my workstation config lives in a GitHub repository, and deploying it onto a new machine is remarkably straightforward.  I have about 70% of what I need captured in code; now I just need to be reasonably diligent about keeping up with changes I make post-installation, and next time around I will be much happier.</p>

<p>Current ruling on Boxen:</p>

<p>Pro:</p>

<ul>
<li>configuration captured in code</li>
<li>safe to re-apply config repeatedly</li>
<li>upstream maintainers quite responsive to pull requests</li>
</ul>


<p>Con:</p>

<ul>
<li>no simple way to handle apps that require post-installation configuration (maybe capture <code>.plist</code> files in the repo as templates? yuck)</li>
<li><em>really</em> does not play nicely with multiple local users on the same host (I may have to end up abandoning my habit of maintaining one user account for work and one for personal use, and leveraging <a href="http://www.controlplaneapp.com">ControlPlane</a> to compensate)</li>
</ul>


<p>-steve</p>

<p>P.S. Oh right, I had also stumbled belatedly onto this Garamond silliness via <a href="http://www.thomasphinney.com/2014/03/saving-400m-font/">this excellent refutation</a>.  My only contribution to the debate, such as it is, is to suggest that Garamond is weaksauce and that real toner-savers use <a href="http://ecofont.com/">Ecofont</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
